the-blueprints.com 2019-11-07

# Privacy Policy

This page is only available in english. 

### Introduction

This Privacy Statement explains how The-Blueprints.com (The-Blueprints.com is owned, built, and maintained by EVOlution Graphics B.V., located in Hilversum, The Netherlands.) processes personal data and for which purpose this data is processed. The Privacy Statement can be consulted at [www.the-blueprints.com](https://www.the-blueprints.com/) and will be send to you on request. 

### Input personal data by Users

As a user (“User”) of the services of The-Blueprints.com (the "Website"), you will have to enter personal details, such as your name, date of birth and e-mail address in order to register a user account and to place orders or to upload your blueprints and/or other content. After an account is created, credits may be purchased in order to purchase products on the Website. To finalize the user account, the User enters its bank and payment details in order Website’s store credit (“Credits”). The number of Credits can be found on the Credit balance in the User account. 

### Purposes of data processing

EVOlution Graphics processes personal data solely for Website related and only for a determinable amount of purposes. Personal data will therefore not be used for any other purposes than those mentioned hereafter. The main objective of the Website is to collect and offer Users a wide range of blueprints and vector drawings (“Products”) of as many different subjects as possible. The data you provide will be used for the following purposes: 

### Creating a User account

To be able to use our services you need a User account. In order to register such an account we need your e-mail address in order to send a verification e-mail and a User ID in order to keep track of your purchases and Credit balance. 

### Credits

We keep your personal details, payment details, User ID and order numbers in order to administer every purchase you make, and to keep track of your current Credit balance. 

### Legal confirmation

We gather your data, such as your name and e-mail address in order to successfully complete every purchase of Credits, or purchases using Credits and to be able to send a confirmation e-mail concerning the purchases you make. We need your date of birth in order to verify that you are at least 16 years old and thus legally able to accept this privacy statement and to enter into agreements with us. 

### Uploading your own blueprints

We need your name and e-mail address when you upload your own blueprints to the website in order to verify you as the uploader of the image, and to be able to send you a confirmation via e-mail. 

### Improvement of the Website

In order to improve our Website and to offer you the best quality of service that we are able to provide, we collect your usage data and personal details. 

### Consent

EVOlution Graphics takes the utmost care in retaining your personal data. By registering your account, ordering a Product or uploading content, you give your explicit consent that we are allowed to process the data you have provided in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Users that have not yet reached the age of 16 will need their parents’ or guardians’ permission. Consent for the processing of your data is temporary and may be withdrawn by you at any time. By withdrawal of consent, Users will not be able to use the Website. 

### Retaining data for use and processing by provider

EVOlution Graphics retains the entered personal data of the User for use in accordance with this Privacy Statement. This data will be retained on the hosting provider of the Website ("Provider"). The Provider controls all data traffic regarding the Website such as, but not limited to, storing Website offered products and services, User accounts and saving data. The Provider undertakes sufficient technical and organizational safety measures regarding the process of personal data in order to prevent data loss or unlawful use of data. The Provider undertakes that said safety measures are compliant to a level that is not unreasonable, with regard to the state of the art, costs and the level of personal data that is processed. In order to make sure that the Provider lives up to these standards, EVOlution Graphics entered into a processing agreement with the Provider. 

### Time limits on retaining data

EVOlution Graphics will not retain any data longer than necessary and only in compliance with the Privacy Statement and in no event will personal data be retained after deletion of the User account. If no longer necessary, the data will be deleted. Deleting your User account will result in deletion of all data that has already been retained. 

### Insight into User data

Your personal data will be available at all times for review and/or alterations on your personal User account page on the Website. Changes to (incorrectly entered) personal details can be made by you in your account details page on the Website. Please note that no purchases can be made if not all personal details are correct. Furthermore, it is possible for you to request, per e-mail, information regarding processing your personal data. By deleting your User account on the Website, all stored personal data will be deleted. 

### Cookies

In addition to personal details, The-Blueprints.com also collects data concerning your interaction with our website. This may include, but is not limited to, your IP address, website surfing behavior, clicking behavior, location details, cookie ID and contact history with our staff. These Cookies are only used to store your Member session ID. This Member session ID is a string of random characters and contains none of your personal data. Use of Cookies is subject to the Cookies policy of the Website and can be consulted on [www.the-blueprints.com/information/cookies/](https://www.the-blueprints.com/information/cookies/) and will be send to you on request. 

### Distribution of data to third parties

EVOlution Graphics will not share your personal data with third parties for commercial, charitable or idealistic purposes. Personal data will only be shared in accordance with this Privacy Statement and not unless you have provided specific permission to do so. 

### Distribution of data to the government

EVOlution Graphics will only distribute your personal data to competent criminal detection authorities or government agencies when this is obligatory under applicable law or by order of a government agency, and only to the extent that such a distribution is strictly necessary for the purposes of preventing fraud or criminal activity. 

### Amendments

EVOlution Graphics reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement. Any changes to this policy will be posted on the Website. We therefore advise you to regularly consult the Privacy Statement. In case considerable amendments to this Privacy Statement are made, which can be of influence on the processing of personal data, EVOlution Graphics will inform its Users beforehand. 

### Records of processing activities

In accordance with applicable regulation, EVOlution Graphics holds a register of the processing activities for which it is responsible. This register does not include detailed information regarding the User. 

### Questions

If you have any questions or complaints regarding the processing of your personal data and/or this Privacy Statement and use of your personal data, you are able to contact us at: <https://www.the-blueprints.com/information/contact/>. We aim to respond to your questions within four weeks. We take the utmost care in protecting and processing your personal data. If, however, you would like to leave a formal complaint, EVOlution Graphics refers you to the Dutch DPA. 

**2000 - 2019 EVOlution Graphics B.V., Hilversum, The Netherlands**
